



<u>josh-atwal.com</u>

josh.atwal@outlook.com

# Josh Atwal

# **Data Scientist, Software Engineer**

With a Master's degree and hands-on experience from an early-stage SaaS startup, I've cultivated a talent for quickly navigating unfamiliar landscapes. My last role had me involved in: backend engineering and architecture, machine learning/data science, cloud infrastructure, database admin, LLM prompt engineering, web scraping, and more.

By combining research and execution I can hit the ground running and confidently tackle any challenge I am given.

In my spare time I frantically keep up with the latest in AI and consume many books/podcasts on technology, philosophy, and psychology. I also love hiking, play the drums, and am addicted to bouldering. Recently, I have been generating AI art and writing about it as a creative outlet.

# **Recent Experience**

Personal projects and more thorough descriptions are available on my website.

#### **FOUNDING ENGINEER**

# Y CoffeeAl | 2021-2023

- Founding team (pre-seed) of a SaaS startup.
- Followed the company through the Y-Combinator accelerator program and multiple product pivots.
- Predominantly worked as a backend Python developer but other roles/responsibilities included data scientist, architect, prompt engineer, devops, cloud infrastructure, DB admin, and content marketer.
- Relied upon to independently solve difficult engineering problems. Worked as part of a development team and managed interns.

#### **MASTERS STUDENT**

#### Luma Analytics | 2021

- Using data to improve the analytics and insights available for amateur golfers, and uncover trends in the sport.
- Involved PCA, clustering, data visualisation, web scraping.
- Self-directed research with low-touch supervision.

#### **COMPUTER VISION ENGINEER**

#### Beca | 2020-21

- An end-to-end computer vision solution encompassing data labelling, model training, and prediction validation.
- Researched contemporary computer vision models before implementing two of them in PyTorch, tuning them to the dataset, and comparing their performance.
- Acted as Product Owner and team leader, self-directing the project with minimal supervision.

# **Education**

## **Masters in Data Science**

- University of Auckland 2020-2021
- First Class Honours

# Bachelor of Engineering / Bachelor of Science (conjoint)

- University of Auckland 2015-2019
- First Class Honours
- Final semester spent on exchange in Germany at the University of Freiburg

# **Technical Skills**

- Data Science, Machine Learning, Statistics
- Generative AI, LLM prompt engineering
- Python, Flask, Pandas
- SQL and database administration
- Kubernetes, Cloud infrastructure (GCP), Elasticsearch,
- Github Actions

# References

Available upon request.